Felix Sylvest Olesen

+852 63980687 | felixolesen@gmail.com | Tooting, London, SW17 9TW
Github | LinkedIn | Itch.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A dedicated and excited Computer Science graduate with industrial experience creating and working on software for testing and education. I am a passionate student of cutting-edge Game Development techniques and design patterns. Along with participating in GameJams I love to make and test video games in my free time.

SKILLS

C++, C#, Python, Unity, Unity ML Agents, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Full-Stack Web Development, Svelte, VueJS, Tailwind CSS, SQL, JQuery, Ruby on Rails, Trilingual Communicator (English, Danish, Spanish)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern, ICHK

December 2023 - February 2024

- ∉ Refactored custom alert PHP code in Gibbon resulting in a more object-oriented codebase.
- ∉ Re-designed the library catalogue feature to have Netflix-like rails UI and bookshelf-style backend using Tailwind CSS and SQL, making the catalogue more engaging for students.
- ✓ Communicated with students and teachers directly to create a clear and meaningful scope for the library catalogue feature and house points module in Gibbon.

Associate Test Engineer, Sky

June 2021 – July 2022

- ∉ Developed a replacement test tool using VueJS and Flask to send video-on-demand assets to test machines through the Sky backend, ensuring continued VOD test coverage.
- ∉ Automated my test cases using an in-house Python testing framework, enabling faster test coverage and improved time management.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) with Sandwich Year, Computer Science

July 2023

University of Surrey Grade Average: 79.6%

Dissertation: Game Tester AI (Reinforcement Learning)

July 2022 – July 2023

Grade: 82%

- ∉ Created a novel game testing AI using adversarial reinforcement learning and imitation learning which produced an AI with improved generalizability and training efficiency compared to the first implementation developed by SEED.
- ∉ Documented the research process in a thesis document, communicating and testing the improvements of the AI in accessibility and generalization.

University Project: Parallel Computing

January 2021 – July 2021

Grade: 88%

- Conducted a series of optimization tasks emulating how the kernel in a computer allocated memory depending on access to the GPU through CUDA. Completing this task allowed me to demonstrate a deeper understanding of low-level computation and how computers function.
- Demonstrated expertise in parallelism and C++ through analysis of memory allocation between global and shared memory through optimizing matrix multiplication tasks.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GameJam Participant, Aquetect

March 2024 - Present

- ∉ Participated in the PixelJam 2024 GameJam to create a game under the theme "Aqua"
 as a seven-day event, resulting in making a "Rollercoaster Tycoon-like" Aqueduct builder
 and manager game using a pixel-art top-down isometric art style.
- ∉ Planned a seven-day project lifecycle to develop a playable product within the time frame of the GameJam, resulting in an efficient creation and learning experience.

Indie-Game Developer, Bugs Tower Defense

July 2023 - March 2024

- Created a demo tower defense video game and published it on Itch.io to learn the full game development process from scratch to a playable, polished product.
- Play-tested the tower defense game extensively to minimize bugs and received feedback from friends and family to improve the overall gameplay experience and gamebalancing.

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

2022 - Published Research Paper on Novel Optimization Algorithm

2019 – University of Surrey Prestige Scholarship

2019 - ICHK Growth Mindset Scholarship B

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- ∉ Game Development I make games as a hobby and always have a GameJam or indiegame project I'm working on.
- ∉ Touch Rugby Played competitively in Hong Kong leagues even facing off against a team captained by the French national team captain (former world number 1 team).